<readings>
  <day0>
    <reading1 content="Isa+60:1-7"><![CDATA[<h3 class="s1">The Future Glory of Israel</h3> <p class="q1"><sup id="Isa.60.1" class="v">1</sup> Arise, shine, for your light has come,</p> <p class="q2">and the glory of the <span class="nd">Lord</span> has risen upon you.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="Isa.60.2" class="v">2</sup>For behold, darkness shall cover the earth,</p> <p class="q2">and thick darkness the peoples;</p> <p class="q1">but the <span class="nd">Lord</span> will arise upon you,</p> <p class="q2">and his glory will be seen upon you.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="Isa.60.3" class="v">3</sup> And nations shall come to your light,</p> <p class="q2">and kings to the brightness of your rising.</p> <p class="b"></p> <p class="q1"><sup id="Isa.60.4" class="v">4</sup> Lift up your eyes all around, and see;</p> <p class="q2">they all gather together, they come to you;</p> <p class="q1"> your sons shall come from afar,</p> <p class="q2">and your daughters shall be carried on the hip.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="Isa.60.5" class="v">5</sup>Then you shall see and be radiant;</p> <p class="q2">your heart shall thrill and exult, </p> <p class="q1">because the abundance of the sea shall be turned to you,</p> <p class="q2"> the wealth of the nations shall come to you.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="Isa.60.6" class="v">6</sup>A multitude of camels shall cover you,</p> <p class="q2">the young camels of Midian and Ephah;</p> <p class="q2">all those from Sheba shall come.</p> <p class="q1"> They shall bring gold and frankincense,</p> <p class="q2">and shall bring good news, the praises of the <span class="nd">Lord</span>.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="Isa.60.7" class="v">7</sup>All the flocks of Kedar shall be gathered to you;</p> <p class="q2">the rams of Nebaioth shall minister to you;</p> <p class="q1"> they shall come up with acceptance on my altar,</p> <p class="q2"> and I will beautify my beautiful house.</p> <p class="b"></p>]]></reading1>
    <reading2 content="1Sam+2:1-10"><![CDATA[<h3 class="s1">Hannah’s Prayer</h3> <p class="p"><sup id="1Sam.2.1" class="v">1</sup>And Hannah prayed and said,</p> <p class="b"></p> <p class="q1"> “My heart exults in the <span class="nd">Lord</span>;</p> <p class="q2"> my horn is exalted in the <span class="nd">Lord</span>.</p> <p class="q1">My mouth derides my enemies,</p> <p class="q2">because I rejoice in your salvation.</p> <p class="b"></p> <p class="q1"><sup id="1Sam.2.2" class="v">2</sup> “There is none holy like the <span class="nd">Lord</span>:</p> <p class="q2">for there is none besides you;</p> <p class="q2">there is no rock like our God.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="1Sam.2.3" class="v">3</sup>Talk no more so very proudly,</p> <p class="q2">let not arrogance come from your mouth;</p> <p class="q1">for the <span class="nd">Lord</span> is a God of knowledge,</p> <p class="q2">and by him actions are weighed.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="1Sam.2.4" class="v">4</sup> The bows of the mighty are broken,</p> <p class="q2">but the feeble bind on strength.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="1Sam.2.5" class="v">5</sup>Those who were full have hired themselves out for bread,</p> <p class="q2">but those who were hungry have ceased to hunger.</p> <p class="q1"> The barren has borne seven,</p> <p class="q2"> but she who has many children is forlorn.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="1Sam.2.6" class="v">6</sup> The <span class="nd">Lord</span> kills and brings to life;</p> <p class="q2">he brings down to Sheol and raises up.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="1Sam.2.7" class="v">7</sup> The <span class="nd">Lord</span> makes poor and makes rich;</p> <p class="q2"> he brings low and he exalts.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="1Sam.2.8" class="v">8</sup> He raises up the poor from the dust;</p> <p class="q2">he lifts the needy from the ash heap</p> <p class="q1"> to make them sit with princes</p> <p class="q2">and inherit a seat of honor.</p> <p class="q1"> For the pillars of the earth are the <span class="nd">Lord</span>’s,</p> <p class="q2">and on them he has set the world.</p> <p class="b"></p> <p class="q1"><sup id="1Sam.2.9" class="v">9</sup> “He will guard the feet of his faithful ones,</p> <p class="q2">but the wicked shall be cut off in darkness,</p> <p class="q2">for not by might shall a man prevail.</p> <p class="q1"><sup id="1Sam.2.10" class="v">10</sup> The adversaries of the <span class="nd">Lord</span> shall be broken to pieces;</p> <p class="q2"> against them he will thunder in heaven.</p> <p class="q1"> The <span class="nd">Lord</span> will judge the ends of the earth;</p> <p class="q2">he will give strength to his king</p> <p class="q2"> and exalt the horn of his anointed.”</p> <p class="b"></p>]]></reading2>
    <reading3 content="Rom+6:1-14"><![CDATA[<h3 class="s1">Dead to Sin, Alive to God</h3> <p class="p"><sup id="Rom.6.1" class="v">1</sup>What shall we say then? Are we to continue in sin that grace may abound?<sup id="Rom.6.2" class="v">2</sup>By no means! How can we who died to sin still live in it?<sup id="Rom.6.3" class="v">3</sup>Do you not know that all of us who have been baptized into Christ Jesus were baptized into his death?<sup id="Rom.6.4" class="v">4</sup>We were buried therefore with him by baptism into death, in order that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, we too might walk in newness of life.</p> <p class="p"><sup id="Rom.6.5" class="v">5</sup>For if we have been united with him in a death like his, we shall certainly be united with him in a resurrection like his.<sup id="Rom.6.6" class="v">6</sup>We know that our old self was crucified with him in order that the body of sin might be brought to nothing, so that we would no longer be enslaved to sin.<sup id="Rom.6.7" class="v">7</sup>For one who has died has been set free from sin.<sup id="Rom.6.8" class="v">8</sup>Now if we have died with Christ, we believe that we will also live with him.<sup id="Rom.6.9" class="v">9</sup>We know that Christ, being raised from the dead, will never die again; death no longer has dominion over him.<sup id="Rom.6.10" class="v">10</sup>For the death he died he died to sin, once for all, but the life he lives he lives to God.<sup id="Rom.6.11" class="v">11</sup>So you also must consider yourselves dead to sin and alive to God in Christ Jesus.</p> <p class="p"><sup id="Rom.6.12" class="v">12</sup>Let not sin therefore reign in your mortal body, to make you obey its passions.<sup id="Rom.6.13" class="v">13</sup> Do not present your members to sin as instruments for unrighteousness, but present yourselves to God as those who have been brought from death to life, and your members to God as instruments for righteousness.<sup id="Rom.6.14" class="v">14</sup>For sin will have no dominion over you, since you are not under law but under grace.</p>]]></reading3>
    <gospel content="Matt+28:1-6"><![CDATA[<h3 class="s1">The Resurrection</h3> <p class="p"><sup id="Matt.28.1" class="v">1</sup> Now after the Sabbath, toward the dawn of the first day of the week, Mary Magdalene and the other Mary went to see the tomb.<sup id="Matt.28.2" class="v">2</sup>And behold, there was a great earthquake, for an angel of the Lord descended from heaven and came and rolled back the stone and sat on it.<sup id="Matt.28.3" class="v">3</sup> His appearance was like lightning, and his clothing white as snow.<sup id="Matt.28.4" class="v">4</sup>And for fear of him the guards trembled and became like dead men.<sup id="Matt.28.5" class="v">5</sup>But the angel said to the women, “Do not be afraid, for I know that you seek Jesus who was crucified.<sup id="Matt.28.6" class="v">6</sup>He is not here, for he has risen, as he said. Come, see the place where he lay.</p>]]></gospel>
  </day0>
</readings>
